A Guide to the Seward Forest Papers, 1900-1989 (bulk 1920-1925)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Papers of the Seward Forest
  - Subseries A: Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1949 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, A-C 1950 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, D-L 1950 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, M-S 1950 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1950 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, A-C 1951 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, D- 1951 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, I-M 1951 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, N-S 1951 (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1951 (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, A-R 1952 Jan-1953 Jan (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, S-Z 1952 Jan-1953 Jan (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1953 Jan-1954 Jun (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, C-J 1953 Jan-1954 Jun (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, K-S 1953 Jan-1954 Jun (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1953 Jan-1954 Jun (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, A-D 1954 Jul-1957 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, E-H 1954 Jul-1957 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, I-L 1954 Jul-1957 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, M-N 1954 Jul-1957 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, O-S 1954 Jul-1957 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1954 Jul-1957 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, A-C 1957 Jul-1959 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, D-K 1957 Jul-1959 Jun (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, L-R 1957 Jul-1959 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, S-Z 1957 Jul-1959 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1959 Jul-1962 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, C-F 1959 Jul-1962 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, G-M 1959 Jul-1962 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondencce, N-T 1959 Jul-1962 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, U-Z 1959 Jul-1962 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, A-M 1962 Jul-1964 Jun (Box 37)
    - Correspondence, N-T 1962 Jul-1964 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, U-Z 1962 Jul-1964 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, A-G 1964 Jul-1967 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, H-M 1964 Jul-1967 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, N-S 1964 Jul-1967 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1964 Jul-1967 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, A-G 1967 Jul-1970 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, H-M 1967 Jul-1970 Jun (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, N-R 1967 Jul-1970 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, S-T 1967 Jul-1970 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, U-Z 1967 Jul-1970 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, A-L 1970 Jul-1972 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, M-Q 1970 Jul-1972 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, R-T 1970 Jul-1972 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, R-T 1970 Jul-1972 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, U-Z 1970 Jul-1972 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, A-G 1972 Jul-1974 Jun (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, H-O 1972 Jul-1974 Jun (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, P-T 1972 Jul-1974 Jun (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, U-Z 1972 Jul-1974 Jun (Box 40)
    - Correspondence - Final Days of Seward Forest 1971-1975 (Box 40)
  - Subseries B: Topical Files
    - Actual and Estimated Expenditures and Budget Allowance, Seward Forest 1947-1974 (Box 40)
    - Allotment Balances (Seward Forest), University of Virginia Bursar's Office 1948-1951 (Box 40)
    - The Amphibians and Reptiles of the Seward Forest by W. Leslie Burger ca. 1960 (Box 40)
    - Annual Reports of the Seward Forest 1936-1946 (Box 40)
    - Annual Reports of the Seward Forest 1947-1959 (Box 41)
    - Annual Reports of the Seward Forest 1960-1966 (Box 41)
    - Annual Reports of the Seward Forest 1967-1974 (Box 41)
    - Budget Notes, Seward Forest 1935-1943 (Box 41)
    - Budget Notes, Seward Forest 1944-1946 (Box 41)
    - Budget Notes, Seward Forest 1947-1954 (Box 41)
    - Conservation and the Environment n.d., 1964-1972 (Box 41)
    - Estimated Expenditures, Seward Forest 1934-1948 (Box 41)
    - Fire at the Seward Forest Sawmill 1956 (Box 41)
    - Forestry Committee Meetings 1954-1957 (Box 41)
    - Forestry, General, Seward Forest n.d., 1947-1970 (Box 41)
    - Forestry Legislation 1954-1961 (Box 41)
    - Forestry Statistics (primarily Virginia) 1953-1963 (Box 42)
    - Forestry Teaching/Instruction n.d., 1948-1957 (Box 42)
    - Founder's Day 1937-1962 (Box 42)
    - Infrastructure (Roads, Ponds, Graveyards, Bridges), Seward Forest 1937-1963 (Box 42)
    - Insects and Diseases 1953-1959 (Box 42)
    - Markets for Wood Products 1932-1968 (Box 42)
    - Motor Vehicles 1935-1962 (Box 42)
    - Newspaper Clippings n.d., 1952-1974 (Box 42)
    - Photographs (Seward Forest) n.d., 1910, 1940, 1952, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Plantations (Tree Plantings) on Grounds at University of Virginia 1929-1940 (Box 43)
    - Tree Plantation Diagrams, University of Virginia 1928-1929, 3 items (Box 43)
    - Prices for Lumber and Wood, Seward Forest 1952-1963 (Box 43)
    - Proposed Forestry and Boy's Camps at Seward Forest 1957-1965 (Box 43)
    - Blueprints for Camp Buildings n.d., 1936, 1957, 12 items (Box 43)
    - Surveying Records n.d., 1933, 1968 (Box 43)
    - Two-Year Junior Colleges, Virginia 1954-1967 (Box 43)
    - Utilities (Water, Electric, Septic), Seward Forest 1939-1963 (Box 43)
    - Seward Forest Water Works Map, Mecklenburg Electrical Co-op Right of Way 1939, 1955, 1957, 5 items (Box 43)
    - Visitors and Tours, Seward Forest 1948-1973 (Box 43)
    - Work Crew Correspondence, A-B 1936-1954 (Box 43)
    - Work Crew Correspondence, C 1936-1954 (Box 43)
    - Work Crew Correspondence, D-H 1936-1954 (Box 43)
    - Work Crew Correspondence, I-N 1936-1954 (Box 44)
    - Work Crew Correspondence, O-R 1936-1954 (Box 44)
    - Work Crew Correspondence, S-Z 1936-1954 (Box 44)
    - Work Crew Notes, Seward Forest n.d., 1941-1950 (Box 44)
  - Subseries C: Seward Forest Workers' Time Records and Other Bound Volumes
    - Budget Heads 1935-1936 (Box 44)
    - Custom Sawing and Dressing 1945-1953 (Box 44)
    - Farm Accounts 1932-1936 (Box 44)
    - General Expenditures 1935-1948 (Box 44)
    - Growing Stock 1935-1943 (Box 44)
    - Seward Farm journal 1857-1888, 1 folio volume. (Box 44)
      Kept by [W. M. Seward, Isle of Wight County, Va.]; farm records; veterinary remedies; and births, marriage, and deaths of family and slaves.
    - Income Record 1937-1958, 6 volumes (Box 45)
    - Mess Account ca. 1935-1944 (Box 45)
    - Notebook Kept by Alfred Akerman ca. 1901 (Box 46)
    - Notebook (Branch Place, Seward Forest Survey) n.d., 1940-1958 (Box 46)
    - Notebook (Moore Field Tract) n.d. (Box 46)
    - Notebook (Survey of Seward Forest) n.d., 1948 (Box 46)
    - Rents and Sales ca. 1934-1944 (Box 46)
    - Rents and Sales 1938-1940 (Box 46)
    - Severance Tax Record 1948-1955 (Box 46)
    - Survey Book ca. 1938-1948 (Box 46)
    - Survey of the Erwin Cotton Mills Tract 1947 (Box 47)
    - Survey of Moorfield and Other Areas ca. 1951-1965 (Box 47)
    - Survey of Trees in Dismal Swamp by Ray H. Barnum ca. 1921-1922 (Box 47)
    - Teacher's Class Books ca. 1908-1941 (Box 47)
    - Tree Records, Dismal Swamp 1921, 2 envelopes (Box 47)
    - Wardens' Records (Brunswick, Chesterfield, Dinwiddie, Greensville, Lunenburg, Nottoway, Surry, Sussex Counties) 1923-1925 (Box 48)
    - Wood for Schools 1939-1940 (Box 49)
    - Worker's Time Records 1935-1958 Aug, 11 envelopes (Box 49)
    - Worker's Time Records 1958 Sep-1962 May, 1968 Dec-1972 Jun, 4 envelopes (Box 50)
    - Yard Office Records 1938-1939 (Box 50)